Send a message
Hello Hello friends Welcome back to my channel
Today I am going to talk about a private
insurance sector company. It is
a great company. You must have heard the name
ICICI General Insurance Lombard. It is a
private sector insurance providing
company which has
also given a good amount of money to its investors.
Due to Corona, there has been a good correction in the purse.
If you are building your portfolio with a long term vision, then
ICICI Lombard must be there in your portfolio.
It is a great company. It
can give you good returns in the future. So let's know about ICICI General Insurance Ltd.
ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited is one of the
leading private sector general insurance
company in India with the gross return
premium of
57.8% of the year and March 31.
It is a great company. The
market capital of large cap companies is 52 thousand 992
crores but its current market price is 1106
111. Its 52-week low is ₹85.
Its value is ₹85.  The stock is of 132 parts, the rate of which is
40, the latest is 22.96%, the
latest is 16.12%,
show the excellent growth in it, in 3 years it is 20.17%
and its face value is ₹10, if you
want to invest in the company for long term or
short term, then you should
invest in it on the basis of its financials and not on the
basis of the company's private moments, so
its sales in June 2017 were 1999 crores,
its sales in June 2017 became 2882 crores,
operating profit fell slightly from 296 crores to 284 crores,
but there has been a slight decline in operating profit, let's
see its profit after tax, which was
300 crores, which has now become 371 crores,
whereas net profit has increased from 214 crores to
282 crores, space is also
growing well, IPS of 4.74 which was
6.20 crores  It is a great company.
With a long-term vision, you
must add it to your portfolio. Let's
look at its profit and loss statement,
which is available in crores in all the features.
In March 2008, its sales
were 1567 crores, which have increased to 11,410 crores today.
Operating
profit used to be around
6 crores, friends, but today it has become positive at 1575 crores. It
is a great company. Profit after
tax, which was 130 crores, has increased to 1697
crores. Net profit has increased
from 103 crores to 1194 crores.
GPS has increased from 2.46 crores to 26.72 crores.
If you add it to your portfolio with a long-term vision,
it
can make you a lot of money.
Due to Corona, it has also undergone a good correction.
This is a very great stock. A
stock that wants to be seen in crores, you must add it to your portfolio with such a long-term vision, only then will
you
become a millionaire in the coming years.
Hello Hi, if we look at the compound sales
growth of Lombard, then the sales growth of juice in 10 years is
about ten and a half to fifteen
percent, whose sales growth in 5 years is
about a quarter percent, the
sales growth in 2-3 years
is more than 20 percent and the
growth seen in it this year is
around 12 and a half percent,
what happens to its profit in compound profit growth,
so in 10 years its profit growth has been
about 24.25 percent, it is growing continuously at 24
percent,
its profit growth in 5 years has been about
8.5 percent, in 3 years
its profit has increased a lot,
what has happened is about 16.5 percent and this year the
growth seen is more than 350 percent, if we
look at the CAGR of this stock, then the data of 10 years, 5 to 3
years is not available, so how
old is its listing, in one year
it has  It has given a return of 1.2 percent. Let's
look at the return on equity.
Its return on equity for 10 years is
11.88 percent. For 5 years it is
17 percent. For 3 years it is around 16 percent.
From last year, its
return on equity is 16.12 percent. This is a
stock worth keeping for the long term. You can include it in your
portfolio once. ICICI General Insurance is
a last-step company. Let us now
see, it has given this type of return so far
and if we visit its return profile, then
in one day it is down by about five and a half percent. In one day it is down by
about nine and a half percent.
In 1 month it has put more than two percent.
In 3 months it has given a return of about twelve and a half percent.
In six months it has given a negative return of about thirteen and a half percent.
In 2020, it has given a
negative return of about fifteen and a half percent. The
return it has given in one year is four and a
half percent.
Whereas in 2 years, the return it has given is  It gave returns that increased to
more than 8%. It is a good company, a
very excellent company. There is no problem with this.
But due to Corona, the entire
market has become well connected.
You must be aware that due to this, even good shares have
come at very cheap valuations. If we
look at the shareholding pattern of IS,
which is till March 2019, then the
maturity shareholders are the promoters.
In this also, plus promoter holding, that is, there is
no problem of pledged shares. A
stay of about 10.5% has been taken on 29 of the mutual funds.
553 schemes of FIR have taken almost 23 per
cent stake, which means if we include F5 mutual
funds, then these two have about 34 per cent
stake. The promoter of
IS holding, which ICICI Bank has a
stake of more than 55.5 per cent. The
highest public shareholder is with
SBI Mutual Fund. In almost two
decades, it has a holding of 9 per cent. And
individual investor holders, that is,
retail investors like you and me, have about 5.5 per cent stake in this.  These
are great companies.
You can add them to your portfolio with a long-term vision.
If you are
building your portfolio for 10-15 years,
then ICICI Lombard General Insurance should definitely be included in
your portfolio.
It will definitely make you rich.